Finding aid for Department of Afroamerican and African Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1966-2010 (bulk 1970-1994)
Bentley Historical Library
- U-Matic Videotapes, 1971-1989
  - 1981-1989
    - Forty-one news items concerning racism and racist incidents at the University of Michigan (Feb 6, 12, 19, and 20; Mar 1, 4, 5, and 6) Radio TV Reports, Inc., 1987
      - Tape 1, 1987 February-March; [2012140-571]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 1:02:42) (Box 45)
        (Forty-one news items concerning racism and racist incidents at the University of Michigan (Feb 6, 12, 19, and 20; Mar 1, 4, 5, and 6) Radio TV Reports, Inc. Tape 1.)
      - Tape 2, 1987 February; [2012140-572]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 10:45) (Box 45)
        (Forty-one news items concerning racism and racist incidents at the University of Michigan (Feb 6, 12, 19, and 20; Mar 1, 4, 5, and 6) Radio TV Reports, Inc. Tape 2.)
    - Twenty-six news items concerning racism (January 11, 12, 13, 14, and 15), Radio TV Reports, Inc., 1988 January; [2012140-573]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 1:02:28) (Box 45)
      (Twenty-six news items concerning racism ( January 11, 12, 13, 14, and 15), Radio TV Reports, Inc.)
    - WXYZ-TV, "Second Look" episode concerning UM people and racism. "8:30 a.m.," Radio and TV Reports, Inc., 1988 April 10; [2012140-574]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 48:17:00) (Box 45)
      (WXYZ-TV, "Second Look" episode concerning UM people and racism. "8:30 a.m.," Radio and TV Reports, Inc.)
    - "Frontline," "Campus Racism", 1988 May 10; [2012140-575]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 57:44:00) (Box 45)
      ("Frontline," "Campus Racism. Radio and TV Reports, Inc.)
    - UCAR Steering, 1989 March 02
      - Originals
        - Part I, 1989 March 02; [2012140-576]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 1:02:36) (Box 45)
          (The United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) Steering [committee?] meets and members share why they got involved with the organization, what impacted their decision, and how they hope the organization to develop and impact the community. This is the first portion of the meeting. UCAR was formed in response to a series of racist incidents on campus. Copies of this meeting exist in tapes 2012140-578, 2012140-579, and 2012140-580.)
        - Part II, 1989 March 02; [2012140-577]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 26:28:00) (Box 45)
          (The United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) Steering [committee?] meets and members share about the future of the organization. This is the second portion of the meeting. UCAR was formed in response to a series of racist incidents on campus. Copies of this meeting exist in tapes 2012140-578, 2012140-579, and 2012140-580.)
      - Copies
        - Part I, 1989 March 02; [2012140-578]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 22:10) (Box 52)
          (The United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) Steering [committee?] meets and members share why they got involved with the organization and what impacted their decision. Segment 1 of 3. UCAR was formed in response to a series of racist incidents on campus. This is a copy of tapes 2012140-576 and 2012140-577.)
        - Part II, 1989 March 02; [2012140-579]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; 22:09) (Box 52)
          (The United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) Steering [committee?] meets and members share how they hope the organization to develop and impact the community. Segment 2 of 3. UCAR was formed in response to a series of racist incidents on campus. This is a copy of tapes 2012140-576 and 2012140-577.)
        - Part III, 1989 March 02; [2012140-580]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; color; sound; 21:38) (Box 52)
          (The United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) Steering [committee?] meets and members share about the future of the organization. Segment 3 of 3. UCAR was formed in response to a series of racist incidents on campus. This is a copy of tapes 2012140-576 and 2012140-577.)
- VHS Videotapes, 1971-2004
  - Undated
    - "A Huey P. Newton Story", Undated; [2012140-594]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:30:08) (Box 46)
      (Roger Guenveur Smith performing "A Huey P. Newton Story," a solo performance representing the life of activist Huey P. Newton.)
    - "Commitment to Diversity", Undated; [2012140-581]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 2:06:30) (Box 46)
      (was formed in response to a series of racist incidents on campus. This is a copy of tapes 2012140-576 and 2012140-577.)
    - "Community Speak Out", Undated; [2012140-582]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:10:57) (Box 46)
      (00:00-1:05:23) Community towne meeting/City Council Meeting? Discussion of local grievances and issues within the Ann Arbor. Includes city council members, the Ann Arbor Police Department, and other city government workers. (1:05:30-1:10:57) Various recordings of television programs and commercials.
    - "Cultural Presentations and Representations", Undated; [2012140-583]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:09:14) (Box 46)
      (History graduate student delivering a paper for a session. Thomas C. Holt, Director of the Center for Afroamerican and African Studies & Professor of American and African American History at the University of Chicago, giving comments.)
    - "Discourse in the African Diaspora: The Language of Musical Symbols", Undated; [2012140-585]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:45:51) (Box 46)
      (Graduate students presenting papers for a session with introductions by Michael Awkward. (0:33-23:08) Guthrie Ramsey, "Towards a Definition and Categorization of Bebop: A historical inquiry." (23:40-41:56) Timothy Taylor on Chuck Berry's "Johnny B. Goode." (42:00-1:05:38) Kyra Gaunt on rap, race, and perception. Responses: (1:05:40) Robert Chrisman, (1:14:35) Michael Awkward. (1:22:23) Q&A.)
    - Graduate Student Conference
      - Dr. Charles Henry, "Keynote", Undated; [2012140-632]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 55:00:00) (Box 48)
        (Keynote speech by Dr. Charles Henry. Graduate Student Conference (later Student of COlor of Rackham, SCOR). [Sound is very low.])
      - Session 1 - Racial and Gender Construction in History, Undated; [2012140-765]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:50:22) (Box 48)
        (The second day of the graduate student conference of Afro American and African Studies at the University of Michigan. Three presentations: Tracy Matthews, Victoria Walcott, Nancy Mirabal.)
      - To Be a Colonial, Session IIA, Undated; [2012140-633]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:51:23) (Box 48)
        (Colonialism is discussed. Speakers include: Otto(?) Gonzalez, John Styles(?), John Foltsmith(?), Joseph Dorcy. Graduate Student Conference (later Student of Color of Rackham, SCOR).)
      - Politics of Race, Session IIB, Undated; [2012140-634]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:43:47) (Box 48)
        (A discussion on the politics of race and social constructions of race and gender. Speakers include: Mary Alice Parker, Nancy Davis, Amy Durdon(?). Graduate Student Conference (later Student of Color of Rackham, SCOR).)
      - Social Science, Session IIIA, Undated; [2012140-635]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:43:22) (Box 48)
        (A discussion with four speakers and two commentators. Speakers include: Dr. Tricia Garret(?) professor of psychology, Ken(?) Hargrove(?) on managing diversity, Chris Mcauley(?) on imperialism, Suzanne(?) Jenkins and on Robin Soler(?), Pedagogy in psychology. Graduate Student Conference (later Student of Color of Rackham, SCOR).)
      - Community Self, Session IIIB, Undated; [2012140-636]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:23:54) (Box 48)
        (Community Self featuring presentations by: Michell(?) Johnson, Sharon Holland(?), and Professor Ruth Bayhal(?). Graduate Student Conference (later Student of Color of Rackham, SCOR).)
    - Joe Dulin, Undated; [2012140-586]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; 1:15:39) (Box 46)
      (Joe Dulin, principal and educator in Ann Arbor, speaking with a class on race relations.)
    - Keefa Lorraine, Undated; [2012140-591]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 2:02:51) (Box 46)
      (Keefa Lorraine, 'The Urban Bush Doctor,' on tapping the fourth dimension.)
    - "LA: It Couldn't Happen Here", Undated; [2012140-590]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:39:07) (Box 46)
      (A panel sponsored by the Ella Baker Nelson Mandela Center. Speakers: Regina Freer on the similarities between LA and Ann Arbor in regards to housing and race relations; Nancy Mirabal speaking on Latinos in LA; Michael Appel and Randy Barnes(?) from the Housing Law Reform Project of Student Legal Services; Mary Ann from the Unity Tenants Organization.)
    - "MLK Day Discussion", Undated; [2012140-593]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 18:58) (Box 46)
      (MLK Day Discussion, a UCAR sponsored session about a film, possibly about Martin Luther King Jr. [see 2012140-581-1])
    - "Perspectives on Planning and Development", Undated; [2012140-595]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 32:14:00) (Box 46)
      (Panel on "Perspectives on Planning and Development." Q&A segment.)
    - Rasul Muhammad, "Decreasing the Gap", Undated; [2012140-584]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 2:51:23) (Box 46)
      (How to the decrease the gap between a black student and the community with guest speaker Rasul Muhammad?)
    - The Retention, Performance and Minority Achievement, Undated; [2012140-600]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:37:39) (Box 46)
      (Speaker talking about research on minority, primarily black, student achievement at the University of Michigan.)
    - Washtenaw County C.V.P., Undated; [2012140-605]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 37:41:00) (Box 47)
      (Children's Visitation Program (CVP), Washtenaw County Jail. Female inmates interact with their children, with dramatic music and cuts added for effect. Interviews with families.)
    - "Women in Transition" Psych 201, Undated; [2012140-606]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 36:32:00) (Box 47)
      (Interviews with various women in transition for Psych 201. Sandra Krull, Cassandra Chaos, Barbara Hohmann, Miss P., Nerissa P. Glynnis Fairbanks, Bobbie, and Melissa. The Shelter Association of Ann Arbor.)
  - 1971-1990
    - Ken Blake, Jim Ingram, Tony Brown, Murry DePillars, "Dedication Ceremonies for the Kuumba Murals", 1971 July 21; [2012140-620]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; b/w; sound; 1:01:33) (Box 47)
    - Raymond Giles, "Separate Black Studies vs. Curriculum Reform" (Comments: William Green; Presider: Parker), 1972 October 21; [2012140-621]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; b/w; sound; 1:05:00) (Box 47)
      (Discussion about teaching separate black studies versus teaching black studies as part of the total curriculum. Presider: Parker. Includes discussion by: Raymond Giles and William Green.)
    - Ben Scott, "Detroit's Hayden: America's Poet Laureate" re: Robert Hayden, 1978 October 11; [2012140-622]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:09:50) (Box 47)
      (Program focused on the life of Robert Hayden. Only goes to 29:06, the rest consists of unexpected content including random TV programs and commercials.)
    - Black Forum, Jan-Apr, University of Michigan program, 1986 January; [2012140-623]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 2:27:50) (Box 47)
      (The Black Student Media Coalition presents "Black Forum." There are several episodes of Black Forum. The calendar for various events is given. Contains various interviews.)
    - "Ethnic Notions" (documentary), 1987; [2012140-587]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 59:57:00) (Box 46)
      ("Ethnic Notions," a documentary of ethnic characterizations and stereotypes in popular culture. Produced, written & directed by Marlon Riggs. Narrated by Esther Rolle. Presented by California Newsreel.)
    - UCAR Protest/Duderstadt News, 1987 March; [2012140-624]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 6:10:41) (Box 47)
      (News coverage of the United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) and their demands to university of Michigan administration, including Provost Duderstadt and President Harold Shapiro. Only goes to 7:12, the rest consists of unexpected content including random TV programs and commercials.)
    - UCAR Protest, 1987 March; [2012140-602]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:15:52) (Box 46)
      (Various news coverage recording of United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR)'s protest and sit-in, prompted by LSA Dean Peter Steiner's comments.)
    - "For the Love of Baby Junkies", 1987 November 23; [2012140-625]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 5:34:57) (Box 48)
      (A program on drug addicted babies. Only goes to 27:17, the rest consists of unexpected content including random TV programs and commercials.)
    - Harold Cruse, Benjamin Hooks, "Living the Dream," Oprah Winfrey Show, 1988 January 18; [2012140-626]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 27:56:00) (Box 48)
      (News report on Filipino elections. Oprah Winfrey Show on racism "Living the Dream." Also Harold Cruse and Benjamin Hooks.)
    - "Racism on Campus: Toward an Agenda for Action," Parts I and II, Governors State University, 1988 March 22
      - Part I, 1988 March 22; [2012140-627]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape) (Box 48)
        (Governors State University and the Johnson Foundation present a national video conference on "Racism on Campus: Toward an Agenda for Action." Moderator Bob Petty. Interviews include: Reginal Wilson, Ben Johnson, Raymond Mack, Dick Williams, John D. Heidke, Charles Moody, James Duderstadt, Beth G. Reed, Tracye Matthews, Mark Chesler.)
      - Part II, 1988 March 22; [2012140-628]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:14:26) (Box 48)
        ("Racism on Campus: Toward an Agenda for Action" is presented live from Wingspread. Looks racism at the University of Wisconsin, Madison. Phi Gamma Delta fraternity controversy. ZBT house situation. Interviews include: Craig Werner, Bernard Cohen, Steve Casanova, Geneva Brown, Donna Shalala, James E. Jones.)
    - UCAR Steering Committee and History, 1989 March 02; [2012140-603]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 3:46) (Box 47)
      (The United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) Steering meeting. UCAR was formed in response to a series of racist incidents on campus. Content ends at 2:49.)
    - Robert Chrisman, "The Cold War vs. the Third World War," Women's Alliance for Nuclear Disarmament Ann Arbor Chapter, 1990 April 08; [2012140-629]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:07:36) (Box 48)
      (The Women's Alliance for Nuclear Disarmament Ann Arbor Chapter hosts Robert Chrisman. He speaks on the Cold War and the future of the Third World.)
    - Dhoruba bin Wahad, Elmira Collins (UCAR), 1990 May 15
      - [Camera 1], 1990 May 15; [2012140-601]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:48:13) (Box 46)
        (Keynote speaker Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad, Black Panther Party leader, speaking on his life and experiences. Elmira Collins, public housing tenant leader, providing the context for present conditions and how to take. Sponsored by the United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) and the Ella Baker-Nelson Mandela Center. Camera 1.)
      - [Camera 2] -- Housing Commission Meeting, 1990 May 15; [2012140-604]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:59:22) (Box 47)
        (00:10-30:55). Keynote speaker Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad, Black Panther Party leader, speaking on his life and experiences. Elmira Collins, public housing tenant leader, providing the context for present conditions and how to take. Sponsored by the United Coalition Against Racism (UCAR) and the Ella Baker-Nelson Mandela Center. [Camera 2]. Ends abruptly. (30:55) Unidentified and unrelated? meeting, somewhat heated, on housing. Ends with chanting: "hey commission have you heard Ann Arbor is not Johannesburg," eventually changing the word "commission" to various commission members.
    - George Lamming
      - George Lamming, 1990 October 24; [2012140-630]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 2:03:55) (Box 48)
        (Opening comments by Earl Lewis. Godfrey Kordogan(?) from Caribbean Students Association presents a plaque of appreciation. Neesha Hanim(?) introduces George Lamming. A lecture by George Lamming.)
      - George Lamming, King/Chavez/Parks Visiting Professor and Writer in Residence, "Culture, Colonialism and the Novel of Childhood," Residential College, 1990 October 25; [2012140-631] (Box 48)
      - George Lamming, King/Chavez/Parks Visiting Professor and Writer in Residence, "Unfinished Journeys: A Reading," Rackham Amphitheatre, 1990 October 11; [2012140-637] (Box 48)
  - 1991
    - Frameworks II (Graduate Student Conference), 1991 February 01; [2012140-588]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:35:31) (Box 46)
      (Graduate Student Conference (later Student of Color of Rackham, SCOR) Frameworks for Afroamerican and African Studies. Graduate students presenting papers for a session with introductions by Earl Lewis. Todd Shaw, "Content and Character: A Theoretical Framework for Examining Black Leadership and Black Mass Principles." Bilinda Straight, "Sub-Saharan African Religion: Indigenous vs. Imperial Power." Cheedy Jaja, "Philosophy and Culture Possibilities for an African Philosophy". Commentators - Lemuel Johnson and Earl Lewis.)
    - CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990", 1991 March 15-16
      - Earl Lewis, "Welcome" and Charles D. Moody, "Opening Remarks," "9:30-10:15 a.m." Tape 1, 1991 March 15; [2012140-638]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 8:09) (Box 48)
        (Earl Lewis introduces the celebration of 20 years of African American and African studies at the University of Michigan. Charles D. Moody gives a welcome and opening remarks. CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990")
      - Darlene Clark Hine, "Keynote Address: Establishing New Paradigms: The Creation and Growth of African Studies," "10:15-10:30 sic. a.m. 1 hour 59 secs." Tape 2, 1991 March 15; [2012140-639]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:01:28) (Box 48)
        (Introduction by Earl Lewis. Keynote address by Darlene Clark Hine: "Establishing New Paradigms: The Creation and Growth of African Studies." Celebrates 20 years of African American and African studies at the University of Michigan. CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990")
      - Earl Lewis, Harold Cruse, Thomas Holt, Bazel Allen, Panel 1: "From BAM to CAAS: Origins and Aims of the Center for African American and African Studies, "10:30-noon" "Tape 3, 1991 March 15-16; [2012140-640]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:32:18) (Box 48)
        [Sound is glitchy throughout; left channel cuts in and out.] Discussion of the University of Michigan experience related to African American and African studies. Moderated by Earl Lewis. Panel discusses: "From BAM to CAAS: Origins and Aims of the Center for African American and African Studies,." Panelists include: Earl Lewis, Harold Cruse, Thomas Holt, Bazel Allen. CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990"
      - Moderator: Ronald Woods; Panelists: Earl Lewis, Michael Martin, William Daniel, Jr., Panel 2: "Models for Africana Studies," "1:30 - 2:45 p.m." Tape 4, 1991 March 15-16; [2012140-641]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; sound; 1:24:32) (Box 48)
        (Panel discusses "Models for Africana Studies." Moderated by Ronald Woods. Celebrates 20 years of African American and African studies at the University of Michigan. Panelists include: Earl Lewis, Michael Martin, William Daniel, Jr. CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990")
      - Moderator: Bazel Allen; Panelists: George Davis, Barbara Ransby, Neil Foley, Panel 3: "New Curriculum Options," Tape 5, 1991 March 15-16; [2012140-642]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:14:00) (Box 48)
        (The third panel of the "Reflections and Revisions" conference. Moderated by Bazel Allen. Celebrates 20 years of African American and African studies at the University of Michigan. The panel discusses: "New Curriculum Options." Panelists include: George Davis, Barbara Ransby, Neil Foley. CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990")
      - Panelists: Abdul Goler, Stephanie Johnson, Roderick Linzie, Devlin Ponte, Day 2 Workshop 1: "The Next Generation of Scholars: Towards a Student-Centered Academy," Tape 1, 1991 March 16; [2012140-643]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:53:41) (Box 48)
        (The second day of "Reflections and Revisions." Celebrates 20 years of African American and African studies at the University of Michigan. Panel discusses: "The Next Generation of Scholars Towards a Student-Centered Academy." Panelists include: Abdul Goler, Stephanie Johnson, Roderick Linzie, Devlin Pont. CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990")
      - Moderator: Tracye Matthews; Panelists: Branda Flanagan, Jan Collins-Eaglin, Linda Chatters, Day 2 Workshop 2: "The Dynamics of Gender in Africana Studies and the Academy," "1:00-2:30 p.m." Tape 2, 1991 March 16; [2012140-644]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:39:16) (Box 48)
        (Day 2 Part 2 of "The Day of the Other." Moderated by Tracye Matthews. Panel discusses: "The Dynamics of Gender in Africana Studies and the Academy." Panelists include: Branda Flanagan, Jan Collins-Eaglin, Linda Chatters. CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990")
      - J. Frank Yates, Arthur F. Thurnau Professor of Psychology, Closing Session: "Challenges for Future Development" Tape 3, 1991 March 16; [2012140-645]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:14:10) (Box 49)
        (Closing Session: "Challenges for Future Development," CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions." Features: J. Frank Yates, Arthur F. Thurnau Professor of Psychology,)
    - Jamaica Study Abroad, 1991-06-24 - 1991-06-26
      - Connie Matthews Tabor, Black Panther Party, Part I and 1991-06-27 "A visit with Easton Lee", 1991 June 26-27; [2012140-647]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 2:02:12) (Box 49)
        (Black Panther Party discussion with Conniee Matthews. Also dated 6/27/1991 the Jamaica Study Abroad group gets a visit from Easton Lee (starts at 1:20:28).)
      - Dr. Elsa Leo-Rhynie, "Status of Women in Jamaica", 1991 June 24; [2012140-646]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:59:33) (Box 49)
        (Students from the Jamaica Study Abroad group meet with Dr. Elsa Leo-Rhynie and discuss "Status of Women in Jamaica.")
      - "Variety Show," Jamaica Study Abroad; and "A visit with Easton Lee", 1991 June 26-27; [2012140-648]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:49:14) (Box 49)
        (6/26/1991 A variety show from the Jamaica Study Abroad group. Also dated 6/27/1991 the Jamaica Study Abroad group gets a visit from Easton Lee (starts at 1:20:28).)
    - South African Initiatives Office (SAIO) Visit to South African Universities, 1991 September
      - EEOC, 1991 September 10; [2012140-607]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 1:00:36) (Box 47)
        (Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) meeting. South African Initiatives Office (SAIO) Visit to South African Universities.)
      - London, 1991 September 06; [2012140-608]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 58:59:00) (Box 47)
        (London meeting. South African Initiatives Office (SAIO) Visit to South African Universities.)
      - Nelson Mandela, 1991 September 10; [2012140-609]; 1 videotape (VHS Videotape; color; sound; 16:52) (Box 47)
        (Meeting with Nelson Mandela. South African Initiatives Office (SAIO) Visit to South African Universities.)